It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
After crossing to Hokkaido, Musashi and his friends helped people being chased by ninjas.
홋카이도에 건너온 무사시 일행은 닌자들에게 쫒기던 사람들을 도왔다.
With Baiken brothers, they pulled the covered wagon, fought with Iga Ninja Forces under Gen'unsai, and took them down.
그리고 바이켄 형제와 함께 포장마차를 끌고, 겐운사이가 거느리던 이하 닌자군과 싸워, 그들을 쓰러뜨렸다.
Kaboom!
쿠콰쾅!
Karakuri Stronghold
카라쿠리 성채이오
It's cold-dasu! So cold-dasu!
아, 춥소. 막 춥소!
I'm gonna freeze-dasu!
아, 얼겠소!
Be quiet, Musashi! A martial artist must not complain about cold weather!
시끄러워, 무사시! 적어도 무예가라는 놈이 춥다고 징징대면 안 된다!
W- what is it-dasu, Osenchan?!
뭐, 뭣이오, 오센짱?!
A- a bear!
고, 곰이야!
Hurry up and play dead-dasu!
으악! 빨리 죽은 척 하시오!
I- I'm not tasty-dasu.
아, 나 맛 없소.
Senhime.
센히메님.
Huh? That bear just spoke-dasu!
어? 곰이 말했소!
Who are you?
당신은?
My master Jūbee has sent me as a messenger.
주베 님이 보내신 사신입니다.
Everything is written here.
모든 건 여기에.
That's a bad way of finding someone-dasu!
사람을 찾는데 그러면 안 되오!
You surprised me so much-dasu!
십년은 감수했소!
What did Mr. Jūbee write?
주베 님이 뭐라고?
It became clear that the plot of removing Senhime is done by Hanzō.
센히메님을 없애 버리고자 하는 음모는 한조의 짓이라 판명.
What?!
뭐라!
That Hanzō?
그 한조가?
Why did you come, Mr. Jūbee?
주베 님이 왜 여기에?
I am here to inquire you about something.
한조 님께 찾아뵐 일이 있어서 왔습니다.
Interesting. So what is it?
호오, 그건 무슨 의미일지요.
As our Lord Ieyasu is here, you'd want to talk to him directly.
이에야스 님이 오셨으니 직접 말씀하시지요.
Lord Ieyasu is visiting!
이에야스 님 행차하신다!
Since you've called me, I'm ready to do whatever you order.
급하게 부르셔서 찾아뵈었습니다. 무엇이든지 이 한조에게 분부만 하십시오.
Well then. Hanzō, I have something to ask you.
좋다. 실은, 한조, 자네에게 묻고자 하는 게 있다.
Yessir. What is it?
예. 무엇입니까?
I heard that you've tried to attack and kidnap my granddaughter Senhime numerous times. Is that true?
자네는 내 손녀인 센히메를 여러 번 공격해, 유괴하려고 했다고 들었는데 사실인가.
It is not true. Why would I do that?
사실이 아닙니다. 제가 어째서 그런 일을.
You're saying that it is false?
사실이 아니라는 건가?
Yessir.
예.
It is nothing more than a fabrication of a party, trying to make me fall into a scheme.
분명 저를 계략에 걸리게 하려는 패거리의 날조입니다.
You have been using this Karakuri Hawk to urgently communicate with your subordinates.
이 카라쿠리 매는 네가 부하와 긴급 연락을 하기 위해 쓰고 있던 것이다.
There was a directive to cut Musashi and Kojirō, and steal Senhime.
무사시, 코지로를 베고, 센히메님을 탈취하라는 지령이었군.
Hanzō, everything is clear as Jūbee investigated about this. Disembowel yourself to reclaim yourself.
한조. 모든 것은 주베가 조사하여 명확하다. 미련 없이 할복해라.
It can't be helped as you've found out.
들켰으니 어쩔 수 없군.
You've finally showed yourself, Hanzō! I will cut down an insurgent!
드디어 정체를 드러냈구나, 한조! 반역자는 베어 버리겠다!
Shut up! Taking down Ieyasu and ruling over the whole Jipangu is my objective.
닥쳐라! 이에야스를 쓰러뜨리고 지팡구를 이 손으로 지배하는 게 내 목적.
I will smash your treasonous ambition!
그 야망은 단연코 때려 으깨주겠다!
Yakyū Shinkage style, Long Sword of Headwind!
야규 신영류, 역풍의 대도!
Damn!
젠장!
Prepare yourself, Hanzō!
한조, 각오해라!
How naive!
무르군!
Everyone gather! A treachery!
다들 모여라! 반역자다!
I will send all of you to hell. That begins with Senhime!
네놈들을 지옥에 보내 주겠다. 먼저 센히메부터다!
That bastard!
네놈!
I am worried about Senhime, Jūbee.
센히메가 걱정되는군, 주베.
Yessir! I will go meet her right away.
예! 바로 만나러 가겠습니다.
How dare Hanzō do that.
한조가 그런 짓을.
Yessir. Hanzō and his subordinates seem to be already at Hokkaido. Please be careful.
예. 한조 놈들은 진작에 여기 홋카이도에 건너온 듯 합니다. 조심해 주세요.
My master Jūbee is coming to meet you at the moment.
주베 님도 바로 만나러 오시고 계십니다.
Understood.
알겠습니다.
Princess!
공주님!
Musashi! They're here!
무사시! 왔다!
Got it!
그렇소!
You guys! Acting cool won't get you anywhere-dasu!
네놈들! 멋진 척 해도 소용없소!
Niten'ichiryū: Iron Windmill!
이천일류 철풍차!
You bastards! Running away is cowardly-dasu! Have a match with me-dasu!
네놈들! 달아나는 건 비겁하오! 나와 승부를 보시오!
Don't act hastily, Musashi! That was a tryout.
혼자 날뛰지 마라, 무사시. 방금 것은 연습이었을 것이다.
I wonder if Hanzō is nearby.
한조가 주변에 있을까.
Probably.
분명.
Well then. We'll find out his hideout and smash it completely-dasu!
좋소. 숨은 곳을 알아내서 때려부수어 주겠소!
Senhime, are you alright?
센히메 님, 괜찮습니까.
I'm tired. Let's take a break.
지쳤어. 조금만 쉬자.
Yessir.
예.
Musashi!
무사시!
What is it-dasu?
뭣이오?
Senhime is tired. Let's dig a snow hole and take a break.
센히메 님이 지치셨다. 설동을 파서 조금 쉬자.
Understood-dasu.
알겠소.
-Huh? -What's wrong?
-어? -뭔 일이냐?
I can hear somebody-dasu.
누군가의 목소리가 들리오.
I'll go take a look-dasu!
나, 잠깐 보고 오오!
Musashi! Stop!
무사시! 잠깐!
Is somebody there-dasu?
누구 있소?!
Huh?
어?
Help... please... help... help...
도와줘... 부탁이야... 도와줘... 도와줘...
Just a moment-dasu! I'll be right there-dasu!
잠깐 기다리시오! 지금 가오!
Something's not right-dasu.
이상하오.
That was close-dasu!
위험했소!
Onihime! You deceived me with your magic-dasu!
오니히메! 요술로 날 속였겠소!
Hmph. You are too late for that, Musashi.
흥. 지금 알아채봤자 늦다, 무사시.
Prepare yourself!
각오해라!
Onihime! I will face you.
오니히메! 내가 상대해 주겠다.
She ran away...
달아났는가...
Onihime.
오니히메.
It seems that she's under some kind of misery.
그녀는 뭔가 불행을 짊어지고 있는 것 같군.
Kojirō! Quit your showing off and come to rescue me right now-dasu!
코지로! 멋진 척 작작 하고 빨리 구하러 오시오!
Sorry.
미안.
Really!
정말!
I was gonna fall-dasu!
까딱하면 떨어질 뻔했소!
Hmph. That's because you're an imbecile.
흥. 그건 네가 멍청하니까다.
What do you mean by that imbecile-dasu?!
멍청한 건 뭣이오, 멍청한 건!
It's all your fault for being fooled.
속은 네 잘못이다.
I get fooled easily because I'm pure-dasu!
나는 순수하니까 쉽게 속소!
Senhime!
센히메 님!
Stop, Onihime!
멈춰라, 오니히메!
Give Osenchan back-dasu!
오센짱을 돌려주시오!
Aren't you annoying. But that's as far as you go!
성가신 놈들. 그렇지만 여기까지다!
A snowslide!
눈사태다!
This is because you defied me.
내가 대드니까 이렇게 되지.
That mighty Kojirō and Musashi couldn't do anything in front of a snowslide.
그 대단한 코지로와 무사시도 눈사태 앞에서는 이러지도 저러지도 못했다.
Meanwhile, Hanzō was at Karakuri Stronghold.
그 쯤, 한조는 카라쿠리 요새에 있었다.
Lord Hanzō. Welcome to Karakuri Stronghold.
한조 님. 카라쿠리 요새에 온 것을 환영합니다.
Good job, Jiraiyan. I like this perfect stronghold.
좋다, 지라이얀. 훌륭한 요새, 마음에 들었다.
I am grateful.
황송합니다.
It's too bad that I couldn't get Ieyasu at that time, but anyway we'll begin the war to bring Jipangu into my hands!
이에야스 놈을 놓친 건 유감이지만 이 홋카이도를 거점으로서 내 손에 지팡구를 넣기 위한 전투를 시작한다!
Yessir!
예!
Lord Hanzō.
한조 님.
Onihime.
오, 오니히메.
I've caught Senhime.
센히메를 잡아왔습니다.
Good job, But what about Musashi and Kojirō?
오, 잘 했다. 근데 무사시와 코지로는?
They're under a snowslide.
눈사태와 함께.
Good. They're as good as gone. But if Musashi and Kojirō appear, we'll use Senhime as a bait.
좋다. 일단 처형된 것 같군. 무사시 놈들이 만일 온다면 센히메를 미끼로 해야겠어.
Senhime has finally been captured.
결국 잡히고 만 센히메.
What will happen to Musashi and Kojirō swallowed up by a snowslide? Will Karakuri Stronghold be an entrance to hell?
눈사태에 휩쓸린 무사시와 코지로의 운명은? 카라쿠리 요새는 지옥의 입구가 되는가?
Wait for the stormy latter half!
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
So cold-dasu. I might have ended up as an ice-dasu.
엄청 춥소. 까딱하단 얼음덩어리가 되어버릴 뻔했소.
Osenchan! Kojirō! Where are you-dasu?!
오센짱! 코지로! 어디이오!
Osenchan has been taken away and Kojirō's nowhere to be found-dasu...
오센짱은 빼앗겼고 코지로는 행방불명...
What should I do now-dasu?
이걸 어쩌오?
You ninja bastard! Prepare yourself-dasu!
이 자식, 닌자 놈! 각오하시오!
Don't lose your mind, Musashi!
눈 뒤집히지 마라, 무사시!
Kojirō!
코지로!
Don't surprise me like that-dasu!
놀래키지 마시오!
That's my line!
그건 내가 할 말이다!
You're a stupid fidget who happens to be also thoughtless!
멍청한 주제에 경솔한 덜렁이가!
What-dasu?! I don't understand what you're saying, but you're treating me like a fool!
뭣이오?! 의미는 잘 모르겠지만 날 바보 취급하고 있겠소!
Your monad-like character of blowing your top like an instant water over-heater is just like a fiddler crab!
그 걸핏하면 뚜껑 열리는 단세포같은 성격이 마치 꽃발게와 같구나!
Your moronic excavator-like figure is really snobby-dasu!
너야말로 굴착기인 양 멍청한 모습이나 하고 있는 게 참 아니꼽소!
What did you say?!
뭐야?!
Wanna fight-dasu?!
해 볼 셈이오?
Tee-hee.
힣.
Take this!
이랴!
Hey, Musashi! Stop!
임마, 무사시! 멈춰라!
You really did it!
했겠다!
You bastard!
이 자식!
This is nothing!
이 정도야!
Take this-dasu!
먹으시오!
You! Damn! Brat!
이게! 이게! 이게!
That's never gonna work!
그 정도로는 안 되오!
Huh? Musashi! This is not a good time to be doing this!
어? 무사시! 이런 짓이나 하고 있을 때가 아냐!
That's right-dasu. Rescuing Osenchan comes first-dasu.
그렇소. 오센짱을 구하는 게 먼저이오.
Onihime went to the other side. Find her footsteps!
오니히메는 맞은편에 간 것 같다. 발자국을 찾아라!
Got it!
좋소!
These are footsteps of a bear-dasu.
이건 곰의 발자국이오.
Hmm...
음...
There is nothing more than one bird footstep. How about your side?
저기엔 새 발자국 하나가 있다. 거긴 어떠냐?
Only some footsteps of a bear-dasu. I can't find Onihime's footsteps-dasu.
곰 발자국이 있을 뿐이오. 오니히메의 발자국은 안 보이오.
I see. That's not right.
그렇군. 이상하네.
Huh?
어?
This is it!
이거다!
Take a look at these footsteps!
이 발자국을 잘 봐라!
Hm?
음?
A bear walks with four legs. Moreover, its pace isn't this wide!
곰은 네 발로 걷는다. 게다가 이 정도의 보폭은 아니지!
Walking with four legs...
네 발로 걷소.
She left bear footsteps...
곰 발자국을 남겨서...
Yes. She tried to fool us, but we won't be fooled.
그래. 우리를 속일 생각이었겠지만 그렇게는 안 되지.
Kojirō, aren't you clever-dasu.
코지로 머리 좋소.
Of course.
물론이지.
As we've found that out now, let's chase-dasu!
이제 깨달았으니 쫒소!
Yes.
그래.
So you've appeared, Musashi and Kojirō! Let me greet you first.
왔군, 무사시, 코지로! 일단 환영해 주지.
Let's go, Kerokichi!
가자! 케로키치!
You are Jiraiyan!
넌 지라이얀!
You might made me retreat last time, but I'm paying that back today.
전엔 퇴각했지만 오늘은 복수해 주겠다.
Take this!
먹어라!
You bastard!
네이놈!
Aren't you pretty good, Kojirō? But that will be your last.
꽤 하는군, 코지로. 그렇지만 거기까지다.
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, technique of big snowstorm!
a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, a vi ra hūṃ khaṃ, 대설풍술!
A trick like that won't work against me-dasu!
그런 요술에는 안 당하오!
Musashi!
무사시!
Playtime is over. Farewell!
여흥은 여기까지다. 그럼!
Jiraiyan. What a terrifying brat.
지라이얀. 무서운 놈.
Musashi. What a stupid brat.
무사시. 멍청한 놈.
It hurts-dasu! What was that for-dasu?!
아프오! 뭔 짓이오!
Musashi! This is not a time for a chatter! Hurry!
무사시! 쓸데없는 소리 하고 있을 때가 아니다! 서둘러라!
Got it-dasu!
알겠소!
-Don't let him get away! -I know that-dasu!
-놓치지 마라! -알고 있소!
We lost him-dasu!
놓쳐버렸소!
No. They must be around here.
아니, 이 주변인 게 틀림없다.
What's that?
저건?
It must be Hanzō gang's stronghold.
한조 일당의 요새임이 틀림없다.
Osenchan must be here-dasu, too.
여기 있겠소, 오센짱도.
Yes. We must rescue her no matter what!
그래. 무슨 일이 있어도 구해야 한다!
So you're here, Musashi and Kojirō.
왔구나, 무사시, 코지로.
Those abominable bastards who took two of my Four Iga Kings.
내 사천왕 중 둘이나 쓰러뜨린 미운 놈.
They will pay for the hatred of Goemondo and Shuten!
고에몬도와 슈텐의 원한은 오늘로 꽉 갚아 주겠다!
Mr. Jūbee and Mr. Ushiwaka! Hey, even Mr. Benkei's there!
주베 님에 우시와카 님! 어라, 벤케이 님까지!
Mr. Baiken!
바이켄 님!
It's first time we meet again ever since the competition.
무예 대회 이후 처음이구려.
Yeah, it's been a while! But why would all of you gather at Hokkaido?
그려, 오랜만이네요! 그래도 다 모여서 홋카이도에는 무슨 일로?
Actually, we've followed Senhime's course.
사실은 센히메 님의 발자국을 발자취를 따라왔습니다.
They are heading to Daisetsusha from yesterday.
그거라면 어제 대설사에 향했수.
Daisetsusha?
대설사?
We'll have to hurry. Excuse us.
먼저 서두르겠습니다. 죄송.
Hey, wait! What's going on here?
아, 잠깐! 무슨 일이여?
Hanzō has done treachery, and Senhime and others are in danger.
한조가 반역을 저질러 센히메 님 일행이 위험에 처했다고 합니다.
What?!
뭐라!
We've heard that from Mr. Jūbee, and we're going along with him.
우린 주베 님께 이야기를 들어 같이 가던 참이요.
So that was it!
그랬구나!
Then, excuse us!
그럼 이만!
Baiken thought. For the sake of the friendship with Musashi, he would went to save him right away.
바이켄은 생각했다. 무사시와의 우정을 위해서라면 지금 당장 구하러 갔을 터였다.
But his young siblings have just begun having a peaceful life.
그렇지만 어린 형제는 평화로운 생활을 막 시작했을 뿐이었다.
He couldn't throw that life away.
그 생활을 버릴 수는 없었다.
Here, brother! You can take this!
여기, 형! 이거!
Ikken!
잇켄!
See you later, brother!
갔다 와, 형!
Niken!
니켄!
Here's your lunch box! Open it when you're hungry!
여기, 도시락! 배고프면 먹어!
Oharu!
오하루!
Thank you, everyone! I'm going for the friendship with Musashi!
고맙다, 모두! 형은 무사시와의 우정을 위해서 갔다 오겠어!
Wait for me, without getting sick!
건강히 기다리고 있어라!
Brother!
-형! -오빠!
Let's go, Musashi.
가자, 무사시.
Got it-dasu!
좋소!
That's as far as you go, Musashi and Kojirō!
거기까지다, 무사시, 코지로!
First, put your swords down.
먼저 둘 다 칼을 떨어뜨려라.
Don't be absurd-dasu! Get down to here and have a match fair and square-dasu!
개소리 마시오! 여기에 와서 정정당당하게 승부를 보시오!
I have no need for that. Take a look at this!
그럴 필요는 없다. 이걸 봐라!
Osenchan!
오센짱!
Musashi... Kojirō...
무사시... 코지로...
Both of you, drop your swords.
둘 다 칼을 떨어뜨려라.
If you don't, Senhime is no more.
그러지 않으면 센히메의 생명은 없다.
You bastards! Quit with your cowardly actions-dasu!
이놈들! 비겁한 짓은 때려치시오!
Oh, what would you do? Drop your swords, or kill Senhime?
자, 어쩔래? 칼 떨어뜨릴래, 센히메 죽일래?
You must not trust what they're saying.
이 자가 말하는 걸 믿으면 안 됩니다.
Musashi. Kojirō. Fight.
무사시, 코지로, 싸우세요.
Osenchan...
오센짱...
Senhime!
센히메 님!
I could travel freely for the first time ever since I was born thanks to you two. I have no regrets even if I die here.
난 여러분 덕분에 태어나서 처음으로 자유로운 여행을 할 수 있어 행복했습니다. 여기서 죽어도 후회는 없습니다.
Osenchan!
오센짱!
Musashi was a stupid fidgeting glutton, and that made the trip enjoyable. Kojirō was pompous yet strong and dependable.
무사시는 바보에 덜렁대며 먹보였으니까 참 즐거웠어요. 코지로는 아니꼬워도 강하고 믿음직스러웠어요.
Senchan! I'll die with you-dasu!
오센짱! 나도 같이 죽소!
Then, Kojirō, what's your choice?
그럼 코지로, 넌 어쩔래?
I also do not value my life. But instead, keep Senhime alive.
나도 목숨은 아깝지 않다. 다만, 센히메 님의 목숨은 구해 줘라.
I promise.
약속하지.
A desperate moment has come. Musashi and Kojirō can't do a thing.
절체절명의 때가 왔다. 옴싹달싹도 못하는 무사시와 코지로.
Will they manage to rescue Senhime safely?
센히메를 무사하게 구할 수 있을까.
At that moment, Jūbee's group was heading to Daisetsusha.
그 쯤, 주베 일행은 대설사에 향하고 있었다.
On the land of deeply cloudy Hokkaido, will Musashi's dual blade survive?
구름이 짙게 낀 홋카이도의 땅에 무사시의 이도류, 과연 살아남을 것인가?
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
Hokkaido is full of ice.
얼음이 잔뜩 있는 홋카이도.
It's cold! My body is freezing-dasu!
춥소! 몸도 얼어버리겠소!
Mr. Jūbee, Ushiwaka, Benkei, and Baiken have joined the fight and it's a big battle!
주베 씨에 우시와카, 벤케이, 바이켄도 가세해서 대결전!
Facing Onihime, Jiraiyan, and Hanzō's lackies at once is difficult!
오니히메, 지라이얀, 한조의 조무래기까지 상대해야 해서 큰일!
I wonder if it's possible to rescue Osenchan-dasu!
오센짱을 구하는 건 가능할지 모르겠소!
Next story! Ice-Melting Power of Friendship
다음 이야기! 얼음도 녹이는 우정 파워이오
It's a stormy Karakuri Stronghold-dasu!
질풍노도의 카라쿠리 요새이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
Ice-Melting
얼음도 녹이는
Power of Friendship
우정 파워이오
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!